[
    {
        "id": "01",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'はしります' read in word?",
        "answer": "Бігати"
    },
    {
        "id": "02",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'とびます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Пригати, стрибати"
    },
    {
        "id": "03",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'のぼります' read in word?",
        "answer": "Лізти, карапкатись, підніматись"
    },
    {
        "id": "04",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'ふります' read in word?",
        "answer": "Махати"
    },
    {
        "id": "05",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'もぐります' read in word?",
        "answer": "Пірнати"
    },
    {
        "id": "06",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'おします' read in word?",
        "answer": "Натискати, штовхати"
    },
    {
        "id": "07",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'たたきます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Стукати"
    },
    {
        "id": "08",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'ころびます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Падати, валитись"
    },
    {
        "id": "09",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'なげます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Кидати"
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'もちあげます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Піднімати"
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'ふりむきます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Озирнутися"
    },
    {
        "id": "12",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'さかだちます' read in word?",
        "answer": "Стати дибом, стати на руки"
    },
    {
        "id": "13",
        "question": "How is the hiragana 'ぎゃく' read in word?",
        "answer": "протилежний, навпаки"
    }
]